Nikhil N

17, A Street, New Guddadahalli, Bangalore 560026 +91-9110831486

nnikhil4998@gmail.com

<u>Objective:</u> To obtain a software developer position where I can utilize my experience in understanding product requirements, technical specifications, and collaboration with multiple teams to develop and implement quality software solutions.

<u>Summary:</u> Dedicated Operation Analyst with 2+ years of experience in understanding product requirements and technical specifications to develop and implement quality software solutions. Strong skills in collaborating with multiple teams and ensuring successful implementation of complex solutions.

Professional Experience:

Operations Analyst Fidelity National Financial, Inc. April 2021-present

- Understand feature requirements based on the product spec/business requirements document
- ➤ Work on the technical specification for the feature development
- Collaborate with multiple teams if the solution spans different services and understand the functionality of different services
- Own the complete implementation and testing spanning multiple services and implement changes in different services
- Write extensible code which would help the customisation done for an Application
- Responsible for adding the necessary tests and alerts needed for the feature developed in the respective service
- > Be part of team Oncall and help resolve production issues

Process Analyst Visionet Systems Pvt Ltd October 2020-March 2021

- Worked on understanding feature requirements and developing technical specifications for the feature development
- Collaborated with multiple teams for the successful implementation of complex solutions
- Wrote high-quality code that was scalable and easy to maintain
- Conducted code reviews to ensure the code adhered to best practices and met the required quality standards
- Created automated tests to ensure the quality of the code
- > Troubleshot and resolved production issues in a timely manner

Skills:

- Proficient in programming languages such as Java and JavaScript
- > Strong knowledge in Data structure and Algorithms.
- Strong understanding of API specifications of Gateways and Banks
- > Experience in developing technical specifications for feature development
- Excellent problem-solving and troubleshooting skills
- > Strong collaboration and communication skills
- Knowledge of software development lifecycle and agile methodologies

.....

Projects:

- Build a website responsive website to upload a resume copy and take the feedback from the user using Java as Database
- Coded some macro logics in Excel like to convert number to word format.
- Worked on some minor project Vehicle Monitoring System using RFID Technologies.

Certifications:

Full Stack Developer Certification. Computer Networking Certification.

.....

Education:

B.E in Electronics and Communication Engineering Vijaya Vittala Institute of Technology, VTU, Bangalore August 2016-September 2020

PUC in PCMCs B.B.M.P PU Composite PU College, Bangalore August 2014-May 2016

High School, General Subject Ellen Public School, Bangalore May 2013-May 2014

Language's Know: Kannada, Hindi, and English

Hobbies: Listening Music's, Watching Movies, Travelling